# Bo-Ru (Roy) Lu

□ (+1) 510-424-1911 | ☑ roy.brlu@gmail.com | 🌴 nlp.borulu.com | 🖸 boru-roylu | **in** boru-roylu

#### Research Interests

My recent research focuses on improving language models for spoken dialogue systems, with a particular focus on structure learning, model efficiency, and data synthesis. I have a wide-ranging interest in creating conversational AI systems for real-world applications using large language models (LLMs) and deep learning techniques.

#### Education

University of Washington
 Ph.D. in Electrical & Computer Engineering. Overall GPA: 3.9/4.0.

Seattle, WA July 2024 (expected)

Advisor: Mari Ostendorf.

National Taiwan University
 M.S. in Communication Engineering. Overall GPA: 4.0/4.0.
 Advisors: Lin-Shan Lee and Hung-Yi Lee.

Taiwan

2018

National Taiwan University
 B.S. in Electrical Engineering. Overall GPA: 3.7/4.0 & CS-relevant GPA: 4.0/4.0.

Taiwan

2016

# Research Experiences

· Research Assistant at the University of Washington

Fall 2018 - present

- Advisor: Mari Ostendorf.
- Developed a new configuration for encoder-decoder transformer models to boost task performance and increase training
  and inference efficiency on three decomposable tasks (e.g. dialogue state tracking, medical summarization, medical
  question answering).
- Built a collaborative human-LLM framework to synthesize data, enhancing the performance of fine-tuned T5 models for realistic call center applications.
- Developed an unsupervised learning algorithm that automatically extracts dialogue structure to improve transformer performance and summarize call center calls.
- Built a multi-task model of knowledge identification in document-grounded conversations and achieved state-of-theart results in two recent datasets.
- Applied Scientist Intern at Amazon

Spring & Summer 2022

- Mentors: Yang Liu and Dilek Hakkani-Tür.
- Worked on knowledge-grounded response generation for information-seeking dialogues. Integrated reranking loss function into a response generation model to improve the inference efficiency.
- · Research Intern at Google

Summer 2021

- Mentors: Joshua Ainslie and Santiago Ontañón.
- Worked on multimodal representation learning via a joint vision-language transformer that integrates 2-D image positional encoding to account for the relatively spatial relationships between pixel patches in images.

Bo-Ru (Roy) Lu 2

Research Intern at Microsoft
 Summer 2020

- Mentors: Xiaofeng Zhu and Pengchuan Zhang.
- Worked on weakly supervised user question discovery on private customer service data via multiple instance learning.
- Machine Learning Intern at Apple

Spring 2018

- Mentors: Longkai Zhang and Xin Wang.
- Designed and implemented a neural model for QuickPath keyboard input integrated in iOS 13.
- Research Assistant at National Taiwan University

Spring 2015 - Summer 2018

- Advisors: Lin-Shan Lee and Hung-Yi Lee.
- LSTM with connectionist temporal classification (CTC) for text and spoken document summarization.

## **Publications & Preprints**

\* Equal Contribution

- [1] Efficient Encoder-Decoder Transformer Decoding for Decomposable Tasks Bo-Ru Lu, Nikita Haduong, Chien-Yu Lin, Hao Cheng, Noah A. Smith, Mari Ostendorf. Preprint, arXiv 2024.
- [2] Does Collaborative Human-LM Dialogue Generation Help Information Extraction from Human-Human Dialogues?
  - Bo-Ru Lu\*, Nikita Haduong\*, Chia-Hsuan Lee, Zeqiu Wu, Hao Cheng, Paul Koester, Jean Utke, Tao Yu, Noah A. Smith, Mari Ostendor. Conference of Language Model (CoLM) 2024.
- [3] Unsupervised Learning of Hierarchical Conversation Structure Bo-Ru Lu, Yushi Hu, Hao Cheng, Noah A. Smith, Mari Ostendorf. EMNLP Findings, 2022.
- [4] DIALKI: Knowledge Identification in Conversational Systems through Dialogue-Document Contextualization. Zeqiu Wu\*, Bo-Ru Lu\*, Hannaneh Hajishirzi, Mari Ostendorf. EMNLP 2021.
- [5] A Multi-Passage Knowledge Selector for Information-Seeking Dialogues Zeqiu Wu\*, Bo-Ru Lu\*, Hannaneh Hajishirzi, Mari Ostendorf. DialDoc@ACL, 2021.
- [6] Order-Preserving Abstractive Summarization for Spoken Content Based on Connectionist Temporal Classification Bo-Ru Lu, Frank Shyu, Yun-Nung Chen, Hung-Yi Lee, Lin-Shan Lee. Interspeech, 2017.

### Awards and Honors

• Ranked the 1st place out of 23 teams in the shared task 1 at 1st DialDoc workshop, ACL-IJCNLP 2021. 2021

• 2018 Foxconn Techonology Award, Foxconn Education Foundation.

2019 2018

Government Scholarship for Studying Abroad, Ministry of Education, Taiwan.
Long-Term Fellowship for Cultivating Elite Students, Hsing Tian Kong, Taiwan.

2017 - 2022

- Fellowship to support elite students in Taiwan with the acceptance rate of 0.1%.
- · Advanced Speech Technologies Scholarship, National Taiwan University, Taiwan.

2017

- Recognizes students with excellent academic performance in speech processing (3 recipients in the year).
- International Speech and Communication Association Student Travel Grants, ISCA.

2017

• NTU Electrical Engineering 1960 Alumni Scholarship, National Taiwan University, Taiwan.

2015

- Recognizes undergraduates in EECS with excellent academic performance (2 recipients a year).

Bo-Ru (Roy) Lu 3

# **Teaching Experiences**

· CSIE 5440, Intelligent Conversational Bot, NTU CSIE. Instructor: Yun-Nung (Vivian) Chen.

Spring 2017

• EE 5177, Machine Learning, NTU EE. Instructor: Hung-Yi Lee.

Fall 2016

- Lead TA: led the team of 13 TAs and tutored 278 students in the course.
- · CSIE 5431, Applied Deep Learning, NTU CSIE. Instructor: Yun-Nung (Vivian) Chen.

Fall 2016

## Services & Invited Talks

Program Committee (Reviewer)
 ACL ARR 2023-present, ICASSP 2023-2024, AAAI 2023-2024.

· Invited talks.

USC CSCI 535 (Multimodal Probabilistic Learning of Human Communication) 1st DialDoc Workshop at ACL 2021

April 2022 July 2021

### Skills

- · Languages: Mandarin (native), Taiwanese (native), English (fluent).
- Programming Languages: Python, Shell Script, Javascript, HTML/CSS, C++.
- · Libraries: PyTorch, TensorFlow, Hugging Face, Scikit-learn, Numpy, Pandas.
- Tools: Git, Docker, Apptainer/Singularity, Google Clould, Azure, AWS.
- · High Performance Computing (HPC): Slurm, HTCondor

Last updated: July, 2024